athan Cooper

🗷 nacooper01@email.wm.edu | 🏕 nathancooper.io | 🖸 ncoop57 | 🛅 nathan-cooper | 💆 @ncooper57 | 🖫 Nathan A Cooper

Research Interests

Intersection of software engineering (SE) and artificial intelligence (AI), i.e., AI4SE and SE4AI. Specifically, research of AI4SE that interest me are information retrieval, collaborative developer tools, and question & answering systems. For SE4AI, research involving deep learning model testing and interpretability, development life-cycles of AI software systems, and AI software system architectures.

Education

College of William and Mary Williamsburg, VA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 2018 - 2023

University of West Florida Pensacola, FL

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Experience _____

College of William and Mary Williamsburg, VA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Fall 2018 - Present

Auburn University Auburn, AL

Undergraduate Research Assistant Summer 2017

University of West Florida Pensacola, FL Fall 2015 - Summer 2018

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Honors & Awards

S. Laurie Sanderson Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Mentoring, Outstanding undergraduate 2021 Williamsburg, VA mentoring in scholarship and research outside of classroom teaching.

Virginia Space Grant Consortium (VSGC) Fellowship, Researching the application of graph neural 2020-21 networks to solve software engineering tasks. (on going)

Williamsburg, VA

3rd Place, UWF's CodeFest: Developed a multiple player android app named Discoverers to inspire people 2018 to learn more about their planet's geography.

Pensacola, FL

2015 - 2018

Outstanding Student Award, at UWF 2017

Pensacola FI

Journal Publications

- M. Ciniselli, N. Cooper, L. Pascarella, A. Mastropaolo, E. Aghajani, D. Poshyvanyk, M. Di Penta, G. Bavota, "An Empirical Study on the Usage of Transformer Models for Code Completion," In IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE), 2022
- C. Watson, N. Cooper, D. Palacio, K. Moran, D. Poshyvanyk, "Systematic Literature Review on the Use of Deep Learning in Software Engineering Research," In ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), 2022
- N. Wilde, B. Eddy, K. Patel, N. Cooper, V. Gamboa, B. Mishra, K. Shah, "Security for Devops Deployment Processes: Defenses, Risks, Research Directions," In International Journal of Software Engineering & Applications (IJSEA), Nov. 2016

Conference Publications

2022

• A. Ami, N. Cooper, K. Kafle, K. Moran, D. Poshyvanyk, A. Nadkarni, "Why Crypto-detectors Fail: A Systematic Evaluation of Cryptographic Misuse Detection Techniques," In Proceedings of the 43rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland'22), 2022

2021

- N. Cooper, C. Bernal-Cárdenas, O. Chaparro, K. Moran, and D. Poshyvanyk, "It Takes Two to Tango: Combining Visual and Textual Information for Detecting Duplicate Video-Based Bug Reports," in Proceedings of the 43nd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE'21), Virtual (originally Madrid, Spain), 2021.
- M. Ciniselli, N. Cooper, L. Pascarella, D. Poshyvanyk, M. Di Penta, and G. Bavota, "An Empirical Study on the Usage of BERT Models for Code Completion," in Proceedings of the 18th IEEE/ACM Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR'21), Virtual (originally Madrid, Spain), May 17th - 19th, 2021.
- · A., Mastropaolo, S., Scalabrino, N. Cooper, D., Palacio, D., Poshyvanyk, R., Oliveto, and Bavota, G., "Studying the Usage of Text-To-Text Transfer Transformer to Support Code-Related Tasks," in Proceedings of the 43nd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE'21), Virtual (originally Madrid, Spain), 2021.

2020

• C. Bernal-Cárdenas, **N. Cooper**, K. Moran, O. Chaparro, A. Marcus, and D. Poshyvanyk, "Translating Video Recordings of Mobile Apps into Replayable Scenarios," in Proceedings of the 42nd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE'20), Virtual (originally Seoul, South Korea), 2020. (20% acceptance rate) - **ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award**

2017

- B. Eddy, N. Wilde, **N. Cooper**, B. Mishra, V. Gamboa, K. Shah, A. Deleon, N. Shields, "A Pilot Study on Introducing Continuous Integration and Delivery into Undergraduate Software Engineering Courses," In Proceedings of the IEEE 30th Conference on Software Engineering Education and Training (CSEE&T'17), Savannah, Georgia, 2017
- B. Eddy, N. Wilde, **N. Cooper**, B. Mishra, V. Gamboa, K. Patel, K. Shah, "CDEP: Continuous Delivery Educational Pipeline," In Proceedings of the ACM SouthEast Conference (SE'17), Kennesaw, Georgia, 2017

Teaching Experience

CS420/520 Neural Networks for Machine Learning (Undergraduate & Graduate)

TEACHING ASSISTANT: GRADED ASSIGNMENTS AND HOSTED OFFICE HOURS

CS435 Software Engineering (Undergraduate)

INVITED LECTURER AND PROJECT LEAD

TEACHING ASSISTANT: GRADED ASSIGNMENTS AND HOSTED OFFICE HOURS

CS241 Data Structures (Undergraduate)

TEACHING ASSISTANT: GRADED ASSIGNMENTS AND HOSTED OFFICE HOURS

ACM Club's Machine Learning Workshop

PRESENTER

Computer Science Tutor

ASSISTED STUDENTS WITH VARIOUS PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND PRESENTED AND ORGANIZED FRESHMAN LEVEL

WORKSHOPS FOR STUDENTS IN BEGINNER PROGRAMMING AND DATABASE CLASSES

College of William and Mary

Fall 2019, Spring 2020

College of William and Mary

Fall 2019

College of William and Mary

Fall 2018, Spring 2019

University of West Florida

Fall 2016, Spring 2017

University of West Florida

Spring 2016 - Fall 2017

References_

Associate Professor Denys Poshyvanyk (Advisor)

CLASS OF 1953 TERM DISTINGUISHED ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR

• Position: Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: denys@cs.wm.eduPhone: (757) 221-3476

College of William & Mary